Guide to the George Coppola Photographs, 1979-2000 AIS.2003.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
George Coppola Photographs
1975-2000
1990-1999
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Coppola, George
AIS.2003.02
1507 items (Plus few manuscript materials)
The George Coppola Photograph Collection contains photographic prints, negatives, 35mm slides, and manuscript materials documenting various Pittsburgh neighborhoods, special events that occurred in Pittsburgh and, images taken while employed by WPGH-TV, the NFL, and as a self-employed photographer.
Scope and Content Notes
The George Coppola Photograph Collection contains photographic prints, negatives, and 35mm slides taken between 1980-1999 documenting various Pittsburgh neighborhoods, special events, and images. Some were taken while Coppola was employed by WPGH-TV and the National Football League, while others were taken by him as a self-employed photographer. The documents in this collection include letters thanking Coppola for his work, newsletters that credit Coppola for his work in winning awards, and letters of reference written for him.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated to the Archives Service Center by George Coppola in 2003.
Biography
George Coppola worked for WPGH-TV, the NFL, the City of Pittsburgh in the Pittsburgh City Photographer's office, and as a self-employed photographer. His work contributed to several awards won by WPGH-TV including a first place award for print and visual promotion at the Independent Television Association convention.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Previous Citation
George Coppola Photograph Collection, 1980-2000, AIS.2003.02, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into seven series:
Series I. National Football League and Other Athletics
Series II.WPGH
Series III. City Events
Series IV. Phipps Conservatory
Series V. City Places
Series VI. Stock Photos
Series VII. Manuscript Materials
Football -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Photographs; Slides (Photographs); Negatives (Photographic); Correspondence; Mayors -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Photographs; Phipps Conservatory (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Photographs; Neighborhoods -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Photographs; Photographs; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Social life and customs -- Photographs; Business and Industry; Associations; Government; Sports; Pittsburgh Steelers (Football team); National Football League; WPGH (Television station: Pittsburgh, Pa.)
- Athletic and Artistic Events, 1975-1991; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains images dating from the 1980s through the 1990s featuring the Pittsburgh Steelers in games with the Cleveland Browns, the New York Jets, the New England Patriots, the Kansas City Chiefs, the San Diego Chargers, and the Cincinnati Bengals. Other athletic and artistic images included in this series relate to the Pittsburgh Penguins, an ice skating competition, and the Pittsburgh Alloy Dance Company.
  - Pittsburgh Steelers vs. Kansas City Chiefs; Pittsburgh Steelers vs. San Diego Chargers (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Pittsburgh Steelers vs. Cleveland Browns (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Pittsburgh Steelers vs. New England Patriots (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Pittsburgh Steelers vs. New York Jets (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Pittsburgh Steelers vs. Cincinnati Bengals (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Pittsburgh Dance Alloy (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Other Sport Events (Box 1, Folder 7)
- WPGH-TV, 1980-1989; II.
  The images in this series are promotional/advertisement shots created for WPGH-TV depicting Pittsburgh seasons, holidays, important days to remember, a WPGH-TV morning show, and images of a WPGH-TV studio.
  - Stock/Advertisements (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Talk Show Images (Box 1, Folder 9)
- City Events, 1985-1999; III.
  The series contains images documenting Pittsburgh-area events that occurred from the 1990s to 2000, such as the Pittsburgh Marathon and the Garland Park Extravaganza, among others.
  - Children (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Elders (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Garland Park Extravaganza, August 21, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Pittsburgh Marathon (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Other Events (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Phipps Conservatory, 1990-1991; IV.
  This series contains images of two flower shows held at the Phipps Conservatory in 1990 and 1991. Other images in this series are undated.
  - Phipps Fall Show, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Phipps Fall Show, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Phipps Conservatory, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- City Places, 1975-1999; V.
  The images in this series document Pittsburgh neighborhoods.
  - Allentown (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Banksville (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Beechview (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Beltzhoover (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Carrick (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Downtown/The Point (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - East & West Allegheny (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - East Allegheny, Lawrenceville, & Southside (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - East Liberty (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - East Liberty, Garfield & Lawrenceville (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Fineview (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Friendship (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Garfield (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Hazelwoood (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Highland Park (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Homewood (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Larimer (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Lawrenceville (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Mt. Washington (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - North Shore and South Shore (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Northside (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Oakland/Schenley (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Perry North/Hilltop (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Pittsburgh Zoo (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Polish Hill (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Shadyside (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Sheraden (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Southside (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Squirrel Hill (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Strip District (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Unknown Locations (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Three Rivers (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Stock Photos, 1984-1997; VI.
  The images in this series were taken to enhance Coppola's catalog of photographic offerings, serving as a stock photography collection. Topics vary from Pittsburgh city officials and portraits to emergency vehicles, Christmas, music, and others.
  - Beauty Shots (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Chemical and Lab Experiments (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Christmas (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Construction, Sewers, & Warehouse Work (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - EMS, Fire Trucks, & Pounded Vehicles (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Inspections & Investigations (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Mayor & Other City Officials (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Modeling/Headshots (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Music (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Topical (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Police (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Safety (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Manuscript Materials, 1979-1999; VII.
  Items in this series relate to images in the collection. They include correspondence, thank you letters, letters of reference, and newsletters and information from WPGH-TV.
  - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Letters of Reference, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - WPGH-TV Newsletters and Information, 1981-1990 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Garland Park Extravaganza, August 24, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 65)